Guide to the Leverett S. Ropes Papers 1888-1952
Montana Historical Society
- General Correspondence
  - Penobscot Mine, Marysville (re Penobscot and Bald Butte mines; correspondents include H.H. Naftalin, Keith Mackay, H.G. Washburn, J.H. Longmaid; also includes copy of Frank Longmaid's 1894 report), 1932-1934, 1937 (Box-folder 7 / 14)
  - Platner Mine, Prineville, Oregon (re mercury mine; correspondents include Mrs. Frank Platner, H.B. Chessher), 1933-1934 (Box-folder 7 / 15)
  - Prohibition repeal, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 7 / 16)
  - P, 1929-1948 (Box-folder 7 / 17)
  - Quincy Mining Company (re Bald Butte Mine; correspondents include William M. Belcher), 1930-1933 (Box-folder 7 / 18)
  - Reinig Placer Mine, Marysville (correspondents include Edward Reinig, Chauncey A. Graves, Edward P. Scallon, J. Cleveland Haas, G.S. Mobley, E.K. Davis), 1932-1938 (Box-folder 7 / 19)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt administration, 1934, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 7 / 20)
  - Ropes family (re family matters, Michigan and Montana mining ventures; correspondents include Louella, George, Judy, Jack, and Nora Ropes), 1909-1910, 1930-1939 (Box-folder 7 / 21-22)
  - Ropes family (re family matters, Michigan and Montana mining ventures; correspondents include Judy, Louella, Jack, and Leverett Ropes), 1940-1951 (Box-folder 8 / 1-2)
  - Ropes Mine, Ishpeming, Michigan (correspondents include Calumet and Hecla Consolidated Copper Company, James McNaughton, Joe St.Germain, George Curry, Emmet Smith), 1888, 1927-1934, 1941 (Box-folder 8 / 3)
  - R, 1931-1948 (Box-folder 8 / 4)
  - St. Louis Drumlummon Mines, Inc. (re Reconstruction Finance Corporation loan, Marysville mines lease, Helena earthquakes, Ropes' background; correspondents include O.B. Suck, John J. Finley, Henry Sartorius, Kathryn Sullivan, John Way, H.G. Ferguson, C.A. Graves, Wilbur H. Grant, R.M. Elder, Edmund G. Toomey), 1935-1946 (Box-folder 8 / 5-9)
  - St. Louis Mining and Milling Company, Marysville (C.H. Wittenberg), 1930-1932 (Box-folder 8 / 10)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1933-1946 (Box-folder 8 / 11)
  - Sillimanite and corundum (correspondents include Champion Porceline Company, champion Sillimanite, Inc., U.S. War Production Board), 1929-1944 (Box-folder 9 / 1)
  - Silver and Bell Mine, Barker (correspondents include United States Smelting, Refining and Mining Exploration Company), 1931 (Box-folder 9 / 2)
  - Southern Montana Abstract Company (re Beaverhead County township plats; correspondents include Frank Hazelbaker, Keuffel and Esser Company, KLM Process Company), 1930-1931 (Box-folder 9 / 3)
  - Spokane Silver and Lead Mine, Custer, South Dakota, 1931 (Box-folder 9 / 4)
  - John Stansfield (re flotation process), 1931-1934 (Box-folder 9 / 5)
  - Stemwinder Mine, Fort Harrison (T.S. Pryse, C.O. Hartin, J.P. Hiebert, Fred Reynolds), 1930-1938 (Box-folder 9 / 6)
  - Strikes and labor unions (correspondents include Joseph W. Martin, Robert A. Taft, House Committee on Un-American Activities), 1942-1947 (Box-folder 9 / 7)
  - Charlotte Strobel (re mines in Coeur d'Alene District, Idaho), 1939-1948 (Box-folder 9 / 8)
  - Summit Mine, Deep Creek Mining District (correspondents include John Dimeling, Mendota Mining Company), 1930 (Box-folder 9 / 9)
  - S, 1930-1950 (Box-folder 9 / 10)
  - Talc mines (re McKelvey Mine south of Helena; correspondents include John Dimeling, Mendota Mining Company), 1930 (Box-folder 9 / 11)
  - Timberline Lode, Corbin (C.R. Stranahan), 1947 (Box-folder 9 / 12)
  - Tin mines (W.S. Larssen), 1942 (Box-folder 9 / 13)
  - Towley Mines, Marysville (re Shakopee, Home, and other mines; correspondents include Will Rimping, Hugh P. Evans, Armor Martin, Geln G. Hayes), 1940-1942, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 9 / 14)
  - T, 1934-1946 (Box-folder 9 / 15)
  - U.S. Forest Service, Federal Reserve Board, U.S. General Land Office, 1930-1948 (Box-folder 9 / 16)
  - U.S. Geological Survey, U.S. Industrial Advisory Board, U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1933-1949 (Box-folder 9 / 17)
  - U.S. National Recovery Administration, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 9 / 18)
  - U.S. Reconstruction Finance Corporation (re job application, St. Louis Drumlummon Mines, Inc., loan application), 1935-1936, 1942 (Box-folder 9 / 19)
  - U.S. Reconstruction Finance Corporation (re Corporation's policies towards small mines, fluorite; correspondents include Paul Flynn, Joseph W. Pahl, Charles Henderson), 1942-1952 (Box-folder 9 / 20)
  - U.S. Senate War Investigating Committee (re malfeasance of Reconstruction Finance Corporation decisions on corundum, etc.), 1945 (Box-folder 9 / 21)
  - U.S. Supreme Court (re "court packing"; correspondents include Arthur Vandenburg, Burton K. Wheeler, United States News), 1945 (Box-folder 9 / 22)
  - U.S. Treasury Department; U.S. War Production Board, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 9 / 23)
  - United Gold Mines Corporation, Marysville (re Bald Butte and Penobscot mines; correspondents include Edward P. Scallon, Clement K. Quinn), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 9 / 24)
  - United States News, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 9 / 25)
  - U, 1931-1950 (Box-folder 9 / 26)
  - Victory Mine, Ophir Mining District (correspondents include A.H. Johnson, Empire Mining Company, Manley R. McGill, L. Lore Wartes), 1938, 1943-1948 (Box-folder 10 / 1)
  - Vosberg Mining Company, Winston (re Vosberg and Gold Bug mines; correspondents include Ed Vosberg, C.W. Lanaway, Frank Rose, Ray Johnson, James K. Sloan), 1927, 1936, 1938 (Box-folder 10 / 2)
  - V, 1930 (Box-folder 10 / 3)
  - Who's Who in Engineering; Who's Who in Montana; Who's Who in the Northwest; Who's Who in the Western Hemisphere; Who's Who in the World, 1932-1949 (Box-folder 10 / 4)
  - Willard Mine, Warm Springs Gulch, Jefferson County (Robert Connell, A.N. Lund, C.M. Roos), 1913, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 10 / 5)
  - Joseph T. Wilson (re attracting Eastern capital to Montana mining), 1947-1948 (Box-folder 10 / 6)
  - W, 1929-1949 (Box-folder 10 / 7)
  - Z; unidentified, 1941-1948 (Box-folder 10 / 8)
- Court Papers
  - In the matter of the birth of John Lyman Ropes, 1940 (Box-folder 10 / 9)
  - Ropes vs. Bald Butte Mining Company, statement of Leverett S. Ropes, 1905 (Box-folder 10 / 10)
  - St. Louis Mining and Milling Company vs. Montana Mining Company, Ltd., certificate of sale, 1910 (Box-folder 10 / 11)
- Financial Records
  - Income taxes, 1943-1951 (Box-folder 10 / 12)
    RESTRICTED
  - Miscellaneous (includes bills, checkstubs, rent receipts, payroll deductions, tax receipts, etc.), 1930-1949 (Box-folder 10 / 13)
- Legal Documents
  - Dobler Mines, Inc. lease agreements, 1931-1933, 1943 (Box-folder 10 / 14)
  - Elk Creek corundum mine lease agreement, 1943 (Box-folder 10 / 15)
  - Rent and purchase of house from Fred Hooper, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 10 / 16)
  - Thomas Cruse Mining and Development Company trust agreements, 1932 (Box-folder 10 / 17)
- Maps
  - List of maps transferred to Library Map Collection (Box-folder 10 / 18)
- Photographs
  - List of photographs transferred to Photo Archives (Box-folder 10 / 19)
- Printed Material
  - List of printed material transferred to Library (Box-folder 10 / 20)
- Reports
  - Alta Mine, Wickes, 1922 (Box-folder 10 / 21)
  - Basin Gold and Silver Mining Company, 1920 (Box-folder 10 / 22)
  - Calumet Group, Marysville, 1925 (Box-folder 10 / 23)
  - Easter Farm, Jordan, 1927 (Box-folder 10 / 24)
  - "Gold Fields of Montana", 1932 (Box-folder 10 / 25)
  - "Gold Trail" by Julius Ropes (re Ropes Mine, Ishpeming, Michigan, also includes clippings), circa 1890 (Box-folder 10 / 26)
  - Mt. Belmont Gold Mines, Marysville, 1933 (Box-folder 10 / 27)
  - New Departure Mine, Blue Wing Mining District, by George R. Metlen, undated (Box-folder 10 / 28)
  - "Ore deposits of the Little Rocky Mountains, Montana," by Walter Harvey Weed, 1896 (Box-folder 10 / 29)
  - Patented Mines Company property, Scratchgravel Hills, by C. Standish, 1938 (Box-folder 10 / 30)
  - Report on work as mineral surveyor on Lolo National Forest (includes correspondence, field notes, etc.), 1930 (Box-folder 10 / 31)
  - St. Louis Drumlummon Mines, Inc. (reports on Marysville, St. Louis, Drumlummon, blue Bird, and Hickey Mines, tailings, etc.), 1935 (Box-folder 10 / 32)
  - St. Louis Mining and Milling Company (copies of reports by Walter P. Jenney and John R. Parks), 1899, 1901 (Box-folder 10 / 33)
  - Towsley Mines, Marysville, 1919 (Box-folder 10 / 34)
- Speeches
  - "Geology of the Helena Mining District" (speech to Kiwanis Club), 1937 (Box-folder 11 / 1)
  - Helena Mining Region (speeches to Rotary Club), 1929 (Box-folder 11 / 2)
- Writings
  - "Agricultural Vagaries" (re Agricultural Adjustment Administration), 1934 (Box-folder 11 / 3)
  - "The Chicken and the Egg, Which Came First?" (re atomic physics), 1946 (Box-folder 11 / 4)
  - Comment on "Ore Deposits of the Boulder Batholith" (American Institute of Mining Engineers), 1947 (Box-folder 11 / 5)
  - "Corundum", 1929, 1946 (Box-folder 11 / 6)
  - "Helena Earthquakes", 1935 (Box-folder 11 / 7)
  - "Is It a Fair Deal?" (re low bid process), 1941 (Box-folder 11 / 8)
  - "Keno Hill Ice Veins," Yukon territory (drafts of article for Engineering and Mining Journal), 1932 (Box-folder 11 / 9)
  - "Lawlessness" (re prohibition), 1933 (Box-folder 11 / 10)
  - "Looking Backward!" (re Roosevelt Administration), 1934 (Box-folder 11 / 11)
  - "The Marysville District" (Montana Oil and Mining Journal), 1936 (Box-folder 11 / 12)
  - "Mechanics of Ore Injection", 1929 (Box-folder 11 / 13)
  - "The New Deal", 1934 (Box-folder 11 / 14)
  - "Notes on [Harold] Ickes' Proposed Metal Mine Leasing", 1937 (Box-folder 11 / 15)
  - "Origin & Deposition of Economic Minerals", 1929 (Box-folder 11 / 16)
  - "Reversing the Land Policy", 1934 (Box-folder 11 / 17)
- Miscellany
  - Alta Mines, Inc. prospectus (includes extracts from reports by L.S. Ropes and S.T. Hauser, 1922), 1947 (Box-folder 11 / 18)
  - Free Enterprise Uranium Mine, Boulder, (speech by Wade V. Lewis, Elkhorn Mining Company to Exchange Club, Butte), 1952 (Box-folder 11 / 19)
  - Gold Mining Association of America registration card, 1933 (Box-folder 11 / 20)
  - Ishpeming Hotel Company stockholder meeting notices, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11 / 21)
  - List of artifacts transferred to Museum (Box-folder 11 / 22)
  - List of mines operating or accessible in Helena vicinity, 1937 (Box-folder 11 / 23)
  - Mining Association of Montana membership application, description of organization, program, 1945, undated (Box-folder 11 / 24)
  - Montana Corundum Company stock certificate, 1901 (Box-folder 11 / 25)
  - Montana-Silver Tip Mining Company legal agreements, 1928, 1930 (Box-folder 11 / 26)
  - Montana Society of Engineers membership list, circa 1935 (Box-folder 11 / 27)
  - Notebook (re Ropes' Michigan School of Mines thesis on Dead River geology), 1891 (Box-folder 11 / 28)
  - St. Louis Drumlummon Mines, Inc. annual financial statements, 1936-1941, 1946, 1949 (Box-folder 11 / 29)
  - St. Louis Drumlummon Mines, Inc. stock certificate and stock receipt, 1935 (Box-folder 11 / 30)
  - St. Louis Drumlummon Mines, Inc. survey notes, 1935, 1940 (Box-folder 11 / 31)
  - St. Louis Mining and Milling Company deed (includes list of claims), 1934 (Box-folder 11 / 32)
- Clippings
  - Fort Peck Dam, 1934, undated (Box-folder 11 / 33)
  - Government programs, politics, etc., 1931-1949 (Box-folder 11 / 34)
  - Mineral industry, 1931-1949 (Box-folder 11 / 35)
  - Mines (Marysville, Wickes, Rimini, Michigan), 1928-1949 (Box-folder 11 / 36)
  - Mining Association of Montana, 1935-1945 (Box-folder 11 / 37)
  - L.S. Ropes letters to editor, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 11 / 38)
  - Miscellaneous (re science, education, politics, religion, alcohol), 1934-1949 (Box-folder 11 / 39)
- Maps
  - mining related maps [Oversize box], undated (Oversizebox 1)
  - mining related maps [Archives Rolled Map Shelves], undated (Oversize-rolled 1)